

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

☑ sujay.garlanka@gmail.com | 🌴 sujaygarlanka.com | 🗘 sujaygarlanka | **in** sujay-garlanka

Summary .

A graduate student in computer science who has previously worked with enterprise scale data processing, developing APIs and building heavily used open source libraries for developers to interact with those APIs. Also, has experience with full stack development. In addition, enjoys experimenting with new technologies and has a deep appreciation of all components of a technology stack including hardware. Some personal projects showcasing this can be found **here**.

Education

Duke University Durham, NC

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2015 - 2019

 Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Intro to Artificial Intelligence, Operating Systems, Advanced Computer Architecture, Digital Logic Design, Embedded Systems

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2022 - 2024

• Coursework: Analysis of Algorithms, Autonomous Cyber-Physical Systems

Skills

Languages Python, Node.js, Java, .NET, Swift, SQL

Frameworks/Tools Apache Spark, Oclif CLI Framework, Travis CI, Jenkins

Experience _

Box Redwood City, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

August 2019 - June 2022

- Co-leading the migration and rearchitecture of Box API data collection and report generation of 3.8 to 114 billion rows of data daily from cron jobs to Apache Spark jobs. This decreases compute time per cluster and increases system fault tolerance.
- Developed and maintained the open source Box SDKs in Github to allow developers to integrate with Box's API. Over 1.3 million API calls are made every minute through these SDKs.
- Worked with the Java, .NET, Python, Node.js, iOS content, iOS preview SDKs and a CLI.
- Worked on networking in the iOS content SDK by rewriting the network layer to reduce the SDK size by 70%, reducing writes to disk and adding support for video streaming.
- Helped lead the intern interview hiring process, implemented tooling to streamline the process and made the take home project more inclusive and convenient for students.

Technologies: Java, .NET, Python, Node.js, Swift

1 Details Code

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Box Redwood City, CA

• Built an open source command line tool for developers that accesses 200 of Box's API endpoints

Incorporated JSON Web Token (JWT) authentication in the CLI that allows users to securely authenticate with Box to make API calls

- Included features such as interactive CLI with prompting and bulk input/bulk output
- Tool was publicly released and handles around 10k requests per minute

Technologies: Node.js, Oclif CLI Framework, Mocha Testing Framework

Demo C Code

CiscoMorrisville, NC

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

May 2017 - July 2017

August 2017 - December 2017

May 2018 - July 2018

- · Created a proof of concept (POC) for an internal tool to digitize the creation and management life cycle of company legal documents
- Designed and implemented the tool to select the correct form based on user responses, insert the form inputs into a PDF of the appropriate legal document, and track it through the approval and review process
- Integrated it with the DocuSign API for e-signatures and approval

Technologies: AngularJS, Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js

Duke University

Durham, NC

ECE TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Teaching assistant for microelectronics devices and circuits class for Dr. Aaron Franklin
- Held office hours, review sessions and graded homework
- · Awarded TA of the semester